A Guide to the Edward L. Stone/Borderland Coal Company Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Stone Printing and Manufacturing Company Papers
  - Byrd Printing - correspondence with a fellow printer, who seems to have done ads for Ziegfield's Follies, 1909 -1912 (Box Box 128)
  - Waddy & Co. - Everett - correspondence about costs and printing, 1908 -1913 (Box Box 128)
  - State Preservation & Development Commission (see also president camp file) - correspondence and printed remarks about work that Stone Printing did for the Commission (about Caverns of Virginia). Also, friendly correspondence between Stone and certain Commission members, 1929 -1938; (3 folders) (Box Box 129)
  - E. B. Fishburn - printing correspondence, 1910 -1935 (Box Box 138)
  - W. Albert Finlay - printing correspondence, 1921 -1935 (Box Box 138)
  - R. H. Fishburn - brief correspondence about order from Stone Printing, 1910 (Box Box 138)
  - Stone Printing: audits - reports by Ernst & Ernst, 1927 -1930 (Box Box 144)
  - Vollhehr Booklet, photographs, etc. about a Stone Printing job, 1930 -1933 (Box Box 144)
  - The Inland Printer - correspondence that is both friendly and professional about printing techniques and personal affairs, 1917 -1936 (Box Box 144)
  - Miscellaneous "V", including A. Hyatt Verril who authored a book which Stone Printing made illustrations for. Also contains several photographs of waterfalls., 1931 -1935 (Box Box 144)
  - Stone Printing: ELS Stockholders and Directors meetings - notes, letters, minutes, proposals, photographs of local print shops, 1928 -1931 (Box Box 145)
  - Appointments and notices - memos to personnel about parking, etc., 1929 -1930 (Box Box 145)
  - Statements - financial, 1930 (Box Box 145)
  - Individual job costs and prices - detailed accounting records and yearly estimates, 1930 (Box Box 145)
  - Manufacturers Club - announcements of events of the Philadelphia professional association, 1921 -1930; (2 folders) (Box Box 152)
  - Caverns of Virginia - correspondence, photos, proofs, and orders about this Stone Printing publication, 1932 May -1934; (3 folders) (Box Box 152)
  - Associated Advertising Clubs of the World - newsletters and membership information on this business association which Stone must have belonged to through his printing company, 1921 -1928; (3 folders) (Box Box 153)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B" including correspondence with other business companies, 1931 -1935 (Box Box 153)
  - Departments A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, memos to and about these departments of the Stone Printing Co., 1909 -1911 (Box Box 158)
  - H. Heinze - about purchase of machinery for Stone Printing, 1909 (Box Box 158)
  - National Assoc. of Manufacturers - about membership, banquets, and relevant developments (ex: Wagner Labor Disputes Bill 1935), 1917 -1935 (Box Box 159)
  - Pictorial map of Virginia - arrangements about this job by Stone Printing, 1928 (Box Box 161)
  - Joseph W. Little - about printing industry problems, especially open shop, 1919 -1921 (Box Box 163)
  - Stone Printing: C. & O. Railway Co. - job sheets for printing orders performed for C. & O. Railroad Co., 1910; (2 folders) (Box Box 164)
  - U.T.A. - newsletters, booklets, circular letters from the United Typothetae of America (printers) open shop, price fixing, technological developments, 1916 -1918; (3 folders) (Box Box 164)
  - Printing samples - including brochures for the University of Virginia, no date (Box Box 168)
  - Conference Board on Training of Apprentices - reports, letters about this professional (printers) concern, 1916 (Box Box 170)
  - Employing Printers of America - literature, 1920 (Box Box 170)
  - Tariff Printers Society of America - correspondence and samples of tariff schedules done by Stone Printing, 1922 (Box Box 171)
  - TPSA: treasurer's report, including by-laws of society and tariff schedules, 1920 (Box Box 171)
  - TPSA: proceedings of first meeting - several copies of this report on the society's first convention, 1921 (Box Box 171)
  - Lanston Monotype Machine Co. - catalogue and correspondence; Stone Printing was one of Lanston's customers, 1919 -1921 (Box Box 171)
  - Printing costs - letters to printers about expenses and sheets for accounting costs of printing, 1910 -1913 (Box Box 176)
  - National Association of Manufacturers - requests for brochures, programs of meetings, propaganda against unions, information about UTA and open shop, 1913 -1914, no date; (2 folders) (Box Box 176)
  - John S. Leech - letters and forms about apprentice training in printing industry, 1912 -1913 (Box Box 182)
  - House Organ - about printing shop efficiency, ca. 1913 (Box Box 185)
  - International Auto Travel Society - customers of Stone Printing; letters relate to jobs, 1912 -1915 (Box Box 185)
  - Charles E. Stone - letters from Stone to Charles Stone, Managing Director of Stone Printing during Edward's final years, 1934 -1935 (Box Box 188)
  - Stone Printing & Mfg. Co. - financial records, report on a calendar campaign, and correspondence between Stone and company officers, 1929 -1935 (Box Box 188)
  - Stone Printing & Mfg. Co. - letters to customers and layouts for proposed ads, 1931 -1932 (Box Box 188)
  - Directors Meeting: For Attention - brochure and letter from the Southern School of Printing requesting members' support, 1930 (Box Box 188)
  - Circulars - examples of printing, advertisements from different companies, samples of various typefaces, ca. 1930; (3 folders) (Box Box 194)
  - Typographia: An Ode on Printing - clippings, letters, and a copy of the book to which they all refer, a special Stone Printing publication, 1926 (Box Box 195)
  - John A. Morgan - letters and clippings sent between Stone and this fellow UTA member about union affairs and printing costs, 1910 -1916; (2 folders) (Box Box 195)
  - Printers Board of Trade - information on cost calculations, 1907 (Box Box 196)
  - Miscellaneous "P", including letters to and from various printers, 1910 -1911 (Box Box 196)
  - Reports - statements and financial summaries of J. P. Bell & Co. (relation to Stone unknown), 1904 -1905 (Box Box 196)
  - Second Cost Congress - addresses given at this printing congress, 1910 (Box Box 196)
  - Stone System - the paperwork for a system of clocking employees' hours on time cards and sheets, no date (Box Box 196)
  - Miscellaneous "S", including letters to printers about costs and letters about travel plans for cost conventions to hotels, 1910 -1911 (Box Box 196)
  - UTA System - another system of cost accounting designed for printers, 1908 (Box Box 196)
  - Miscellaneous "V-W", including letters to friends in the printing industry, 1911 (Box Box 196)
  - F. E. Wekner & Co. - about printing costs, 1910 (Box Box 196)
  - Miscellaneous letters - the cost congress generated inquiries from printers about the new system of cost finding and these letters, with Stone's replies, are enclosed here. Also letters reminiscing about the congress and enclosing souvenirs and photographs., 1911 -1913 (Box Box 197)
  - Miscellaneous memorandums - clippings and brochures concerning a statewide printers costs congress, which elected Stone as its president, 1909 -1913 (Box Box 197)
  - D. G. Whitehead, Everett Wadey Co., Richmond, Va concerning plans for a general costs congress for the state of Virginia. (Everett Wadey Co. is a stationers store.), 1911 -1913 (Box Box 197)
  - Orders filed on top of index - 5 or 6 purchase orders from coal companies to Stone Printing for stationery, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 197)
  - Union Label - a collection of clippings about unions (especially printers) and their right to strike, 1909 -1913 (Box Box 198)
  - Miscellaneous "V", including circulars and correspondence, especially about Virginia Sanitarium for Consumptives (Stone was on the Board of Directors) and the Victor Cleaner Co. (vacuums), 1906 -1912 (Box Box 198)
  - Miscellaneous "W", including letters about real estate, coal properties, printing orders and charitable contributions to and from: Mrs. J. R. Weaver, John W. Woods, Mrs. N. E. Whitehurst Jr., Edg. C. Wiley, J. H. Wingate, S. A. Weltner, Werner Co., Thomas L. Watson, 1905 -1911 (Box Box 198)
  - Miscellaneous "Y", including letters about charitable donations and personal as well as Stone Printing Co. business, especially to Allen Young (Presbyterian Mission School) and A. A. Yoder (a Stone Printing customer), 1903 -1910 (Box Box 198)
  - Government printing of envelopes - correspondence with congress and other printers about proposal to end government printing of envelopes (pre-stamped and with space for return address) for post office distribution, 1910 -1911 (Box Box 199)
  - Printers District meeting - about plans for a local convention of tariff printers, 1921 (Box Box 199)
  - H. A. Gatchel - about donation to U.T.A. Convention and some printing business, 1910 -1911 (Box Box 199)
  - Gooch-Crosby Co. - about book purchases and picture printing - apparently 2 services offered by this Roanoke business, 1909 -1910 (Box Box 199)
  - J. Frank Eddy - mainly personal correspondence with J. F. Eddy (a friend in the printing industry) with some shop talk, 1907 (Box Box 199)
  - Jn. J. Emerick - about the printing business; Emerick was superintendent for a publishing corporation, 1905 (Box Box 199)
  - John S. Watson - correspondence with this printer friend in Jersey City, chiefly about travels and gifts exchanges, 1913 (Box Box 199)
  - Stone's Photograph Contest - letters, negatives, clippings, entries, winners; run by Stone Printing, 1912 -1913; (3 folders) (Box Box 200)
  - Printing costs "M" - letters to printers about cost finding and the promotion of a unified system, 1911 -1912 (Box Box 203)
  - Printing costs "P-V", 1911 -1912 (Box Box 203)
  - Printing costs "W", 1911 -1912 (Box Box 203)
  - Poole Bros. - letters to/from these "Railway Printers" about printing of tickets and rate schedules, 1910 -1912 (Box Box 203)
  - Tariff letters - miscellaneous correspondence about the printing of railroad tickets; examples of sheets of tickets, 1918 (Box Box 203)
  - Everett Wadey Co.- friendly correspondence with this Richmond printer; occasional mention of union trouble, 1914 -1919 (Box Box 203)
  - Denhem's Cost Finder - a monthly publication devoted to ascertaining costs of production; several issues and supplements are included, 1910 -1912 (Box Box 206)
  - Harold A. Wright - about printing costs; correspondence and actual estimates, 1906 -1907 (Box Box 206)
  - A. M. Glossbrenner - treasurer U.T.A.; correspondence about reimbursement for UTA related expenses, gifts for association officers, etc., 1909 -1913 (Box Box 206)
  - Costs: Lewis C. Gandy - concerning possibility of Stone writing an article for Gandy's "'Printing Art" (about production costs), 1911 (Box Box 206)
  - Miscellaneous "G" - letters to various printers regarding cost finding systems, 1908 -1913 (Box Box 206)
  - Miscellaneous "T-Z" - trivial appeals for donations, ads, etc. from groups, 1913 -1917 (Box Box 217)
  - United Typothetae of America - publications about special printing problems and some correspondence between Stone and officers of the associations, 1918 -1920 (Box Box 217)
  - United Typothetae - Open Shop Division - about printers problems, 1915 -1919 (Box Box 217)
  - United Typothetae of America, Philadelphia, Mr. Franklin W. Heath - correspondence chiefly about cost finding system, 1912 -1913 (Box Box 217)
  - Union - contracts, clippings, members, rules of order for printers' union; material on Stone's struggle against unionism, 1910 (Box Box 217)
  - Miscellaneous "W", including circular letters and brief correspondences with printing associates, 1910 -1919 (Box Box 219)
  - Ware Bros. Co. - about an accusation made about Stone Printing Co. engaging in price cutting in the calendar business, 1913 (Box Box 219)
  - Mitchell & Hotchkiss, Robert Mitchell - friendly correspondence about the state of the printing industry, 1909 -1915 (Box Box 219)
  - R. C. Darby - Piedmont Printing Co. - about the printing business and UTA affairs, 1910 -1912 (Box Box 219)
  - William J. Marrison, New York - concerning the proposed formation of a holding company, 1912 -1913 (Box Box 219)
  - Prices - for the printing of tariffs, 1910 (Box Box 219)
  - U.T. and F.C.A. - committee lists, directories, correspondence, circulars from United Typothetae and Franklin Clubs about prices, open shop, and other printing issues, 1914 Feb. -1915 May; (3 folders) (Box Box 222)
  - J. P. Bell Co. - concerning printing of order blanks, printing costs, etc., 1908 -1910 (Box Box 227)
  - J. M. Dulaney, head of J. P. Bell Co., a printing and publishing firm in Lynchburg. Letters concern printing practices, costs, and upcoming conventions, 1908 -1912 May; (2 folders) (Box Box 227)
  - Franklin Hudson Publishing Co. - costs in printing, 1910 -1912 (Box Box 230)
  - United Printing Machine Co. - catalogues, bills, and letters about orders, 1908 -1909 (Box Box 230)
  - U.T.A. - business correspondence, 1911 -1912 (Box Box 230)
  - Cost Sheets, including various jobs done by Stone Printing, job orders, 1907 -1908, 1913; (2 folders) (Box Box 230)
  - Stone Printing & Mfg. Co. Fortieth Anniversary - anniversary announcements, letters of congratulation, and replies, 1923 (Box Box 234)
  - Stone Printing & Mfg. Co., including Stone's opposition to the union; letters to stockholders and minutes of meetings; some financial statements, as presented to shareholders, 1905 -1929 (Box Box 234)
  - Stone Printing: calendars - letters soliciting calendar orders, 1915 (Box Box 234)
  - Machine composition, including examples of railroad freight rate schedules done by linotype machine, information on linotype vs. monotype printing machines (performance, costs, etc.), ca. 1912; (2 folders) (Box Box 234)
  - Stone Printing & Mfg. Co. - letters to stockholders, 1913 (Box Box 235)
  - Stone Printing & Mfg. Co. - annual statements, 1914 (Box Box 235)
  - Tariff Printers Society - correspondence with society's officers and members about upcoming meetings and ideas for improving tariff printing procedures, 1920 Nov. -1922; (4 folders) (Box Box 242)
  - Correspondence with printing press companies "H" - some of this correspondence relates to Stone's newly patented printing press, 1909 -1912 (Box Box 246)
  - Miscellaneous machinery, letters, cuts, folders, etc., 1910, 1925 (Box Box 246)
  - Crocker-Wheeler Co., 1910 (Box Box 246)
  - Correspondence with printing press companies "M", 1907 -1912; (2 folders) (Box Box 246)
  - Miscellaneous Press, 1907 -1910; (2 folders) (Box Box 246)
  - United Typothetae of America, including correspondence and pamphlets with the Constitution and Code of Ethics, bulletins, 1913 -1914; (3 folders) (Box Box 248)
  - F. R. Hurt (office) - Vice-President and Central Manager of Stone Printing, 1929 -1933 (Box Box 252)
  - C. D. Hurt - correspondence, 1929 -1936; (2 folders) (Box Box 252)
  - Macbain Industrial Corp., 1925 -1935 (Box Box 273)
  - Lanston Monotype Machine Co., 1932 -1935 (Box Box 273)
  - Stone Printing & Mfg. correspondence, 1936 -1937; (2 folders) (Box Box 277)
  - Employing Printers Assoc. of America, including law and labor anti-union periodical, 1921 -1933; (2 folders) (Box Box 283)
  - Stone Printing miscellaneous, 1920, 1929 (Box Box 292)
  - Stone Printing miscellaneous, 1929 (Box Box 295)
  - Stone Printing - financial records and statements, 1936 -1938 (Box Box 309)
  - Stone Printing - monthly statements, 1931 (Box Box 313)
  - White Sulphur Springs - Stone Printing Pamphlet, 1932 (Box Box 313)
  - Typothetae, including Typothetae of Western Pennsylvania, New York, Richmond, Franklin of Chicago, Minneapolis, Minnesota; Typothetae Federation, Fourth District, 1914 -1932 (Box Box 316)
  - Typothetae, Philadelphia - contains manager's weekly letter and correspondence, 1920 -1924 (Box Box 316)
  - Miscellaneous - correspondence and advertisements, (1913), 1930-1935; (2 folders) (Box Box 320)
  - Stone's pictorial map of Virginia - correspondence regarding the map, 1926 -1928 (Box Box 321)
  - Production and labor report - Stone Printing sheets, 1936 (Box Box 322)
  - Arguments - Stone buys out stock from J. P. Bell Co., 1904 (Box Box 325)
  - Tariff Matters - Stone Printing prints tariff sheets for Associated Railways of Virginia & the Carolinas, and there is a dispute over price, 1910 -1914 (Box Box 325)
  - Virginia Historical Index - Stone Printing prints Virginia Historical Index; correspondence, 1934 -1937; (2 folders) (Box Box 328)
  - "Index" comments - comments on Virginia Historical Index, 1934 (Box Box 328)
  - American Type Founders Co., 1913 -1914 (Box Box 334)
  - United Typothetae of America, 1920; (2 folders) (Box Box 335)
  - Southwest Virginia Booklet - The Beckoning Land - booklet published by Stone Printing & Mfg. Co. - correspondence, 1914, 1916; (3 folders) (Box Box 337)
  - Book of Ads for Stone Printing, 1891 (Box Box 338)
  - R. C. Williams - printing related correspondence, 1913 -1917 (Box Box 343)
  - Miscellaneous letters - Stone Printing form letters for Booklet, 1911; (2 folders) (Box Box 353)
  - National Association of Manufacturers, 1912 (Box Box 328)
  - National Association of Manufacturers, 1914 -1915 (Box Box 360)
  - Notes and memorandums, 1908 -1913 (Box Box 360)
  - New York Typothetae, 1913 (Box Box 360)
  - Newspaper cost sheet, 1913 (Box Box 360)
  - Applications, 1909 -1913 (Box Box 361)
  - U.T.A. bulletins and letters, 1909 -1911 (Box Box 365)
  - The Forum - Stone Printing & Mfg. Co. bidding to publish New York based magazine, The Forum, 1928 -1929 (Box Box 391)
  - Requests for catalogues - sent by Stone to nature clubs, furniture dealers, machine companies, etc., 1906 (Box Box 395)
  - Railroad printing charts, cards, etc. - mainly printed instructions for transporting explosives, 1908 (Box Box 395)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "K-L", 1914 -1915 (Box Box 407)
  - Miscellaneous "I", 1909 -1911 (Box Box 410)
  - Miscellaneous "J", 1909 -1911 (Box Box 410)
  - Harvard University Graduate School of Business Administration - program in printing, 1914 -1915 (Box Box 413)
  - W. A. Grant, 1914 (Box Box 413)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "G", 1913 -1914; (2 folders) (Box Box 413)
  - Rep. Carter Glass - on anti-business bill, 1913 -1914 (Box Box 413)
  - C. G. Gooch, 1910 -1915 (Box Box 413)
  - Hall, N. W. Halsey & Co., 1911 -1913 (Box Box 413)
  - Central Mfg. Co., 1911 -1918 (Box Box 413)
  - J. C. Cassell, 1916 -1918 (Box Box 413)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "T", 1916 -1919 (Box Box 413)
  - T. Chalkiadi & Co. Inc., 1913 -1917 (Box Box 413)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", 1913 -1918 (Box Box 413)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "F", 1910 -1911 (Box Box 416)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, mostly from other printers, 1927 -1930 (Box Box 417)
  - William E. Carson, 1931 -1935 (Box Box 418)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", 1912 -1927; (3 folders) (Box Box 418)
  - Chestnut Ridge, 1916 -1921 (Box Box 418)
  - C. & P. Telephone Co., 1920 -1932 (Box Box 418)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "T", 1897 -1936; (3 folders) (Box Box 420)
  - Review of Reviews Co., 1911 (Box Box 420)
  - Panama Canal Photographs, 1911 (Box Box 420)
  - Harry B. Neal - letters to Neal, of Railway Tariff Printers Assoc., along with rules, constitution, and information on printing costs, 1919 -1920; (3 folders) (Box Box 421)
  - Virginia Lines Tariff Bureau about printing tariffs, 1908 -1915; (2 folders) (Box Box 432)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1910 -1915 (Box Box 432)
  - Lanston Monotype Machine Co. - ads, 1915 -1917 (Box Box 433)
  - Menu cards - beautifully engraved menus from special occasions, 1915 -1916 (Box Box 433)
  - Applications from Jan. 1, 1908 to Jan. 1, 1909, for employment at Stone Printing (Box Box 434)
  - Applications up to Jan. 1, 1908, 1907 (Box Box 434)
  - Memos from Stone to Depts. A, B, C, E-J of Stone Printing, 1906 -1908 (Box Box 434)
  - Annual meetings, 1910 -1911 (Box Box 439)
  - Annual reports, no date (Box Box 439)
  - Stone Printing: Map & Mine Directory - letters, orders, and agreements about this project done regularly by Stone Printing on area mines, 1910; (2 folders) (Box Box 440)
  - Southwest Virginia Booklet - letters, orders, plans, and arrangements about the publication of this tourist brochure, 1912 -1913; (3 folders) (Box Box 441)
  - Employing Printers Assoc. - letters, clippings, and newsletters, 1923 -1931 (Box Box 450)
  - Scrapbook of fine printing samples, no date (Box Box 452)
  - Bulletin No. 7 - Advance notice of rate changes, 1911 -1912 (Box Box 452)
  - Correspondence and Papers re Bryant Paper Co., 1931 -1934, n.d. (Box Box 460)
  - Correspondence with various paper companies, 1931 -1935 (Box Box 460)
  - Correspondence with Printing Machine Manufacturers, 1931 -1934 (Box Box 460)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1924 -1935, n.d. (Box Box 460)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material and Photo, 1928, 1936 -1937, n.d. (Box Box 460)
  - 1. [Architect's layout plans], 1911 October 26, including sheets for "First Floor," "Second Floor," and [Basement - Boiler House]. Ink on paper. Includes tables of square footages to be occupied by various departments. The building was constructed on Third Avenue and Jefferson Street, Roanoke, Virginia. Scale: 1/8" = 1' (Box Oversize)
  - 2. [Architect's layout plans], 1914 December 1, including sheets for "First Floor Plan," Second Floor Plan," and [Basement Plan]. Ink on drafting linen. Includes square footages of areas to be occupied by department of the firm. Shows Third Avenue and Jefferson Street. Scale: [1/8" = 1'] (Box Oversize)
  - 3. [Architect's layout sheets, 1914 December 1?]. As above; 4 sheets of 1/4" scale graph paper (Box Oversize)